Finding Aid for Lemuel A. Johnson Papers, 1942-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Writings
  - Criticism
    - American Culture, or the Trouble with Babo's Head, undated (Box 4)
    - "Amo y espero": The Love Lyric, Virginia Brindis de Salas, and the African-American Experience of the New World, 1984 (Box 4)
    - The Art and the Ambiguity of Presence in Literatures of the Black Americas, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Being Foreign, Being Made Foreign: A Rapunzel Effect, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Cross and Consciousness: The Failure of Orthodoxy in African and Afro-Hispanic Literature, 1979 (Box 4)
    - The Devil, the Gargoyle, and the Buffoon: Western Literature and the Idea of Blackness in Human Form
      - Manuscript undated (Box 4)
      - Galley undated (Box 4)
    - The Displays of Genesis, October 27, 2000 (Box 4)
    - A Double Overture, December 1, 2000 (Box 4)
    - (en)Countering Traditions of the Erotic in African Narratives
      - May 16, 2001 (Box 4)
      - July 18, 2001 (Box 4)
      - undated, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - A Genealogy of Violence in Aborigine Literature, undated (Box 4)
    - Genesis and Genitalia
      - 2001 (Box 4)
      - undated (Box 4)
    - Genesis and Genitalia: African Literature and Narratives of the Sexual, undated (Box 4)
    - The Griot is Dead, Long Live the Griot, 1982 (Box 4)
    - History and Dystopia in Alejo Carpentier and Wole Soyinka, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Hottentots, Coolies, and Messiahs: Nationalism and the Response in Literature (The Chinese Experience 1890-1945 The African Experience 1945-1970) [Notes only], undated (Box 4)
    - How to Breathe Dead Hippo Meat, and Live, 1994 (Box 4)
    - The Humanities and the Criterion of Relevance, 1983 (Box 4)
    - The Inventions of Paradise: The Caribbean and the Utopian Bent, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
    - Mahmud Bilateral, or (en)Countering Homosexuality (Box 5)
      - March 18, 2001 (Box 5)
      - undated (Box 5)
    - The Middle Passage in African Literature, undated (Box 5)
    - The (mis)Use of Created Bodies?
      - May 13, 2001 (Box 5)
      - undated (Box 5)
    - Native Bodies: (dis)Counting Sex, (en)Countering Homosexuality, undated (Box 5)
    - No Sweetness Here?: (dis)Counting Homosexuality, 1998 (Box 5)
    - Overtures from a Circling Song, October 12, 2000 (Box 5)
    - The Problem with English Literature, undated (Box 5)
    - Safaris in the Bush of Ghosts: Camara Laye, Saul Bellow, and Ayi Kwei Armah, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Shakespeare in Africa and Essays in the Evidence of Import, undated (Box 5)
    - Shakespearean Imports: Whatever Happened to Caliban's Mother? Or, The Problem with Othello's, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Shoeing the Mule: "Caliban" as Genderized Response, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Sisters of Anarchia, undated (Box 5)
    - Strong Breeds: Wole Soyinka and the Head of the Head of State in "A Play of Giants", undated (Box 5)
    - The Unreturnable--Heaven's Town: Caribbean Literature and the Utopian Bent, (title page and verso), undated (Box 5)
    - Was Shakespeare at Actium and Philippi? Mebi, or mebi no mebi, undated (Box 5)
    - Untitled undated (Box 5)
  - Opinion Pieces
    - First Principles, or How Topsy "Jes Grew," Maybe, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Poetry
    - Before the Facts, undated (Box 5)
    - Carnival of the Old Coast, includes notes
      - 1984 (Box 5)
      - 1994 (Box 5)
      - undated, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - [For Marian], 2002 (Box 6)
    - Hand on the Navel, includes notes
      - 1973 undated (Box 6)
      - 1978 (Box 6)
      - 1994 (Box 6)
      - undated, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Highlife for Caliban, Includes Notes, undated, 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Pompeii, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Sierra Leone Trilogy Introduction, 1985, undated (Box 6)
    - That Was in Another Country, Besides, 1996 (Box 6)
    - (Un)Settling Texts, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified Poems undated (Box 6)
  - Reviews
    - By Johnson 1981-1985, undated, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Short Stories
    - Amy's Case, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Father Northway, in Generation, 1966, 1975 (Box 6)
    - First Glimpses, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Just an Expression, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Melon Flowers, 1969 (Box 6)
    - The Voice of the Turtle (short stories from), undated (Box 6)
  - Translations
    - Nighttime and War in the Prado Museum (An Etching, in a Prologue and One Act), Translated from the Spanish Noche DeGuerra en el Museo del Prado, 1966 (Box 6)
    - The People's Dreamer, Translated from Un Sonador Para Un Pueblo by Antonio Buero Vallejo, undated (Box 6)